[Test]
[Test]
Rafael is different from João Vicente
Rafael é diferente do João Vicente
that is different from me and i'm not like you either
que é diferente de mim e eu também não sou como você
Each person has different tastes, abilities and limitations.
cada pessoa tem gostos,habilidades e limitacoes distintas
but we all have the right to communication, mobility, access to information and leisure
mas todos temos direito a comunicação a mobilidade ao acesso à informação e ao lazer
we all seek autonomy
todos buscamos autonomia
the creation of solutions and the development of equipment
a criação de soluções e o desenvolvimento de equipamentos
are helping people with disabilities or functional problems
estão auxiliando pessoas com deficiência ou com problemas funcionais
to carry out activities and be included in society
a realizarem atividades e estarem incluídas na sociedade
overcoming difficulties through assistive technology
a superação de dificuldades através da tecnologia assistiva
is today's topic by TVE Repórter
é o tema de hoje do TVE Repórter
with a watchful eye and the left hand
com um olhar atento e a mão esquerda
about the adapted mouse
sobre o mouse adaptado
Rafael gives voice to your thoughts
Rafael da voz aos seus pensamentos
tell our team, what is your great passion
conta para nossa equipe, qual é a sua grande paixão
Computer: Popular fans in text
Computador :Torcida Popular em texto
Reporter: Do you watch every game?
Reporter: Assistes todos os jogos?
Reporter: From inter?
Reporter: Do inter?
Selecting letters on the virtual keyboard
Selecionando letras no teclado virtual
He forms the sentence he wants
Ele forma a frase que quiser
But it also manages to access the menu on the computer
Mas também consegue a cessar o menu no computador
Categories in the form of symbols that are engraved
Categorias em forma de símbolos que ficam gravados
facilitating communication
Facilitando a comunicação
The international for example has the placeholder on the home page
O internacional por exemplo tem o espaço reservado na página inicial
and the team lineup is two clicks away
e a escalação do time esta a dois cliques de distância
Reporter: There's a lot of Inter stuff there...
Reporter:Tem bastante coisa do Inter ai...
Computer: Alan Costa, defender
Computador: Alan Costa,Zagueiro
Computer: Maldives, half
Computador: Maldivia,meia
Rafael is 18 years old, and has died since he was 6 at the Menino Jesus de Praga house in Porto Alegre
O Rafael tem 18 anos, e morra desde os 6 na casa menino jesus de praga em Porto Alegre
with cerebral palsy
Com paralisia cerebral
his difficulties are mainly motor
suas dificuldades são principalmente motoras
good-humored.since he was a little boy, he found it easy to make friends
bem humorado.desde pequeno teve facilidade de fazer amigos
the obstacle was the locomotion
o entrave era a locomoção
the solution comes on top of an engine
a solução vem em cima de um motor